elizabethholly.com 2019-12-18

# Privacy Policy - Elizabeth Holly

## Welcome to our Privacy Policy

### Your privacy is critically important to us.

It is Elizabeth Holly’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our website. This Privacy Policy applies to [www.elizabethholly.com](http://www.elizabethholly.com/) (hereinafter, “us”, “we”, or “www.elizabethholly.com”). We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting personally identifiable information you may provide us through the Website. We have adopted this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) to explain what information we may collect on our Website, how we use this information, and under what circumstances we may disclose the information to third parties. This Privacy Policy applies only to information we collect through the Website and does not apply to our collection of information from other sources.

This Privacy Policy, together with the Terms and conditions posted on our Website, set forth the general rules and policies governing your use of our Website. Depending on your activities when visiting our Website, you may be required to agree to additional terms and conditions.

## General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

We are a Data Controller of your information.

www.elizabethholly.com legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described in this Privacy Policy depends on the Personal Information we collect and the specific context in which we collect the information:

  * www.elizabethholly.com needs to perform a contract with you
  * You have given www.elizabethholly.com permission to do so
  * Processing your personal information is in www.elizabethholly.com legitimate interests
  * www.elizabethholly.com needs to comply with the law

www.elizabethholly.com will retain your personal information only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our policies. Our Privacy Policy was generated with the help of [GDPR Privacy Policy Generator](https://www.gdprprivacynotice.com/).

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights. If you wish to be informed what Personal Information we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us.

In certain circumstances, you have the following data protection rights:

  * The right to access, update or to delete the information we have on you.
  * The right of rectification.
  * The right to object.
  * The right of restriction.
  * The right to data portability
  * The right to withdraw consent

## Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Elizabeth Holly collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Elizabeth Holly’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Elizabeth Holly’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Elizabeth Holly may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Elizabeth Holly also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on http://www.elizabethholly.com blog posts. Elizabeth Holly only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below.

## Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Elizabeth Holly’s websites choose to interact with Elizabeth Holly in ways that require Elizabeth Holly to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Elizabeth Holly gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for a blog at http://www.elizabethholly.com to provide a username and email address.

## Security

The security of your Personal Information is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

## Advertisements

Ads appearing on our website may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Elizabeth Holly and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

## Links To External Sites

Our Service may contain links to external sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy and terms and conditions of every site you visit.

We have no control over, and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites, products or services.

## Aggregated Statistics

Elizabeth Holly may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its website. Elizabeth Holly may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Elizabeth Holly does not disclose your personally-identifying information.

## Cookies

To enrich and perfect your online experience, Elizabeth Holly uses “Cookies”, similar technologies and services provided by others to display personalized content, appropriate advertising and store your preferences on your computer.

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Elizabeth Holly uses cookies to help Elizabeth Holly identify and track visitors, their usage of http://www.elizabethholly.com, and their website access preferences. Elizabeth Holly visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Elizabeth Holly’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Elizabeth Holly’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

By continuing to navigate our website without changing your cookie settings, you hereby acknowledge and agree to Elizabeth Holly’s use of cookies.

## Log Files

Elizabeth Holly | The Chronic Wanderer follows a standard procedure of using log files. These files log visitors when they visit websites. All hosting companies do this and a part of hosting services’ analytics. The information collected by log files include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date and time stamp, referring/exit pages, and possibly the number of clicks. These are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. The purpose of the information is for analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movement on the website, and gathering demographic information.

## Google DoubleClick DART Cookie

Google is one of a third-party vendor on our site. It also uses cookies, known as DART cookies, to serve ads to our site visitors based upon their visit to www.website.com and other sites on the internet. However, visitors may choose to decline the use of DART cookies by visiting the Google ad and content network Privacy Policy at the following URL – <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>

## E-commerce

Those who engage in transactions with Elizabeth Holly – by purchasing Elizabeth Holly’s services or products, are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Elizabeth Holly collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Elizabeth Holly. Elizabeth Holly does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

We collect information about you during the checkout process on our store.

## What we collect and store

While you visit our site, we’ll track:

  * Products you’ve viewed: we’ll use this to, for example, show you products you’ve recently viewed
  * Location, IP address and browser type: we’ll use this for purposes like estimating taxes and shipping
  * Shipping address: we’ll ask you to enter this so we can, for instance, estimate shipping before you place an order, and send you the order!

We’ll also use cookies to keep track of cart contents while you’re browsing our site.

When you purchase from us, we’ll ask you to provide information including your name, billing address, shipping address, email address, phone number, credit card/payment details and optional account information like username and password. We’ll use this information for purposes, such as, to:

  * Send you information about your account and order
  * Respond to your requests, including refunds and complaints
  * Process payments and prevent fraud
  * Set up your account for our store
  * Comply with any legal obligations we have, such as calculating taxes
  * Improve our store offerings
  * Send you marketing messages, if you choose to receive them

If you create an account, we will store your name, address, email and phone number, which will be used to populate the checkout for future orders.

We generally store information about you for as long as we need the information for the purposes for which we collect and use it, and we are not legally required to continue to keep it. For example, we will store order information for XXX years for tax and accounting purposes. This includes your name, email address and billing and shipping addresses.

We will also store comments or reviews, if you choose to leave them.

This includes Printful as the manufacturer and shipping party of the ecommerce arrangement. View Printful’s Policy.

## Who on our team has access

Only Elizabeth Holly has access to your information in the form of team access. She operates her blog and ecommerce store as an individual.

## What we share with others

We share information with third parties who help us provide our orders and store services to you; for example —

### Payments

We accept payments through PayPal. When processing payments, some of your data will be passed to PayPal, including information required to process or support the payment, such as the purchase total and billing information.

Please see the [PayPal Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) for more details.

### WooCommerce Services

**Data Used:**  For payments with PayPal or Stripe: purchase total, currency, billing information. For taxes: the value of goods in the cart, value of shipping, destination address. For checkout rates: destination address, purchased product IDs, dimensions, weight, and quantities. For shipping labels: customer’s name, address as well as the dimensions, weight, and quantities of purchased products.

**Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** For payments, we send the purchase total, currency and customer’s billing information to the respective payment processor. Please see the respective third party’s privacy policy ([Stripe’s Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/privacy/) and [PayPal’s Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/privacy/)) for more details. For automated taxes we send the value of goods in the cart, the value of shipping, and the destination address to TaxJar. Please see TaxJar’s [Privacy Policy](https://www.taxjar.com/privacy-policy/) for details about how they handle this information. For checkout rates we send the destination ZIP/postal code and purchased product dimensions, weight and quantities to [USPS](https://www.usps.com/) or [Canada Post](https://www.canadapost.ca/), depending on the service used. For shipping labels we send the customer’s name, address as well as the dimensions, weight, and quantities of purchased products to [EasyPost](https://www.easypost.com/). We also store the purchased shipping labels on our server to make it easy to reprint them and handle support requests.

## Akismet

We collect information about visitors who comment on Sites that use our Akismet anti-spam service. The information we collect depends on how the User sets up Akismet for the Site, but typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).

## Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Elizabeth Holly may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Elizabeth Holly’s sole discretion. Elizabeth Holly encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

## Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

## Embedded Content

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

## Credit & Contact Information

This privacy policy was created  with assistance at [termsandconditionstemplate.com](https://termsandconditionstemplate.com/privacy-policy-generator/ "Privacy policy template generator"). If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us via [email](mailto:elizabeth@elizabethholly.com).

## Other Policies

Jetpack’s privacy policy can be found [here](https://jetpack.com/support/comments/#privacy).

WordPress’s privacy policy can be found [here](https://automattic.com/privacy/).

Google’s Policy [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads).

Printful’s Policy here.

## Consent

By using our website, you hereby consent to our Privacy Policy and agree to its terms.
